Episode 18
第 18 集
ma'am.
女士。
Shen...
沉...
Mother, look at Shen.
妈妈，你看沉。
my son
我的儿子
How can that be?
怎么可能？
How could he die?
他怎么会死呢？
Stop.
停止。
Put your hands away.
把你的手拿开。
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
to...
到...
- I don't want you here. - honey.
- 我不想让你在这里。 - 蜂蜜。
- He died because of you. - honey!
- 他是因为你而死的。 - 蜂蜜！
He died because of you. I know that?
他因为你而死。 我知道？
to!
到！
He's still worried about you...
他还是担心你...
Until his last breath.
直到他最后一口气。
- He died because of you. - honey.
- 他是因为你而死的。 - 蜂蜜。
- You are the culprit. - ma'am.
- 你是罪魁祸首。 - 女士。
- I don't want you here.
- 我不想让你在这里。
- Everything is your fault. - ma'am.
- 一切都是你的错。 - 女士。
let's go Come on, ma'am.
我们走吧 来吧，女士。
You can go too.
你也可以去。
My beloved daughter...
我心爱的女儿...
This isn't your fault.
这不是你的错。
Your mother is overcome with grief.
你的母亲悲痛欲绝。
He didn't mean to say that.
他不是故意这么说的。
Don't take it to heart.
别放在心上。
Dad thought...
爸爸以为...
I am already raising a useless son.
我已经 养了一个没用的儿子了。
And everything he does...
而他所做的一切...
Just harass us.
就是骚扰我们。
But now he's dead...
但现在他死了……
And I have a feeling Dad won't mind cleaning up the mess...
我有预感，爸爸不会介意收拾残局……
Someone made it.
有人做到了。
That person is useless...
那个人没啥用……
And I never want to change it.
我从来不想改变它。
but...
但...
at last...
终于...
He did an impressive job.
他的 工作令人印象深刻。
He makes us very proud.
他让我们非常自豪。
for years...
多年...
Dad worked hard and accomplished everything.
爸爸努力工作， 完成了一切。
To get promoted.
为了升职。
His father plans to pave the way for him.
他的父亲 打算为他铺平道路。
Now that he's gone...
现在他走了...
The position of the head waiter...
领班的位置...
It doesn't matter to Dad anymore.
这对爸爸来说已经不重要了。
Dad said...
爸爸说...
Would you mind thinking about what I said earlier?
你介意考虑一下我之前说的话吗？
my beloved daughter
我心爱的女儿
You have done a lot for your family.
你为你的家人做了很多。
maybe...
或许...
Dad was wrong.
爸爸错了。
your sister...
你妹妹...
You are not suited to become a trader in the first place.
你一开始就不适合成为一名交易者。
If dad gives up his greed...
如果爸爸放弃他的贪婪......
Will power and wealth grow faster?
权力 和财富会增长得更快吗？
This probably won't happen.
这可能不会发生。
my beloved daughter
我心爱的女儿
Now we only have you.
现在我们只有你了。
You said you didn't want to live in Hwangcheong.
你说你不想住在黄清。
Well, we won't stay here.
好吧， 我们不会留在这里。
From now on...
今后...
Dad will take your advice.
爸爸会采纳你的建议。
Dad will resign.
爸爸要辞职了。
Are you hurt?
你受伤了吗？
I happened to.
我碰巧。
Kian...
基安...
I bought this brocade satin a few days ago.
我 前几天买了这块锦缎。
The color is white. Your favorite color.
颜色是白色。你最爱的颜色。
They say there is nothing like this in the world.
他们说世界上没有这样的事情。
I heard you're coming home today...
听说你今天要回家...
So I spent a lot of money on this.
所以我 在这上面花了很多钱。
Try on a dress made from this fabric...
试穿用这种面料制成的连衣裙......
And Tuan will be crazy about you.
Tuan 一定会为你疯狂的。
this!
这！
charming.
迷人。
ma'am.
女士。
Does it smell familiar?
是不是闻起来很熟悉？
no.
不。
Kian.
基安.
Never buy jewelry...
从来不买首饰...
Since marrying into the Zhong family...
自从嫁入钟家之后……
So I bought it especially for you...
所以我专门买 给你的...
Kian...
基安...
You are the daughter of our family.
你是我们家的女儿。
You are beautiful...
你很美丽...
And there are many people who like you.
而且喜欢你的人还有很多。
There is no need to suffer at Zhong Residence.
在钟府就不用受苦了。
I remember everything you said.
你说的一切我都 记得。
Why don't you trust me?
你为什么不相信我？
Kian...
基安...
I have been in prison for a long time.
我已经在监狱里待了很长时间了。
Why didn't you come see me?
你为什么不来看我？
I told you to rest...
我告诉过你要休息...
And he said he would come later.
他说他稍后会来。
I waited all day and you didn't show up.
我等了一整天 你都没有出现。
Kian...
基安...
Kian.
基安.
Is it this painful...
有这么痛吗...
What if you get hit by an arrow?
万一被箭射中怎么办？
I am your older brother.
我是你的哥哥。
How could I stay still...
我怎么能不动呢...
When you see yourself in danger?
当你看到自己处于危险之中时？
Don't be afraid, Qian.
别害怕，钱。
I'm doing great.
我很好。
I will protect you.
我会保护你。
Kian...
基安...
ma'am.
女士。
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
See, madam?
看到了吗，女士？
ma'am?
女士？
- Brother... - Madam!
- 兄弟... - 女士！
sisters.
姐妹。
ma'am.
女士。
Huaxian.
滑县。
Hua Shen is dead.
华神死了。
Do you know?
你知道吗？
me too..
我也是..
I was hit by an arrow in the chest.
我的胸部被箭射中。
Why am I safe...
为什么我安全...
And didn't he?
他不是吗？
Why didn't he survive?
他为什么没有活下来？
Am I dreaming?
我在做梦吗？
Maybe he wasn't dead.
也许他还没有死。
I can still hear it...
我还是能听到...
I can still hear his voice.
我仍然能听到他的声音。
I heard...
我听说...
sigh...
叹...
about me.
关于我。
Madam, are you okay?
女士，您还好吗？
I'm not...
我不是...
I don't have any older siblings.
我没有年长的兄弟姐妹。
- Madam... - This is my second time.
- 女士... - 这是我第二次。
second.
第二。
That's not important.
那不重要。
I am here.
我在这里。
I will never leave.
我永远不会离开。
I will be by your side forever, ma'am.
我会永远在你身边，女士。
The Hua family's eldest son died young.
华家大公子早逝。
What happen?
发生什么事？
Look at.
看着。
my son
我的儿子
Shen!
沉！
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
ma'am.
女士。
Why is it so noisy outside?
外面怎么这么吵？
Today is Mr. Hwa’s funeral.
今天是华先生的葬礼。
Madam, would you please get up and get dressed ?
女士，请您起床穿好衣服好吗 ？
I don't want to go.
我不想去。
I don't want to attend the funeral.
我不想参加葬礼。
Don't wake me up.
别叫醒我。
You must attend your brother's funeral.
你必须参加你哥哥的葬礼。
It's approaching noon.
已经快到中午了。
If you don't go...
如果你不去...
People will gossip.
人们会说闲话。
Are you crying?
你在哭吗？
How did you get here?
你是怎么来到这里？
I was invited to attend the funeral.
我被邀请参加葬礼。
Who let you in?
谁让你进来的？
Are all the servants dead?
仆人都死了吗？
Kian.
基安.
I am your husband...
我是你丈夫...
So they won't stop me.
所以他们不会阻止我。
what?
什么？
You're being nice to me...
你对我很好...
Out of sympathy...
出于同情...
Or because you feel guilty about me?
还是 因为你对我感到愧疚？
What kind of person do you think I am?
你觉得我是一个什么样的人？
Kian!
基安！
- Chenz - Chen!
- 陈兹 - 陈！
I know you're upset...
我知道你很烦恼...
But I have to do my hair...
但我必须做头发...
And get dressed before you leave.
并在离开前穿好衣服。
What does that have to do with you?
这和你有什么关系？
I'm here to get you back.
我是 来接你回来的。
Take me back? Where are you going?
带我回去？ 你要去哪里？
Are you returning to your servant’s residence?
你要回仆人住处吗？
I'm watching you and Mu Yao...
我在看着你和慕瑶……
Sharing love with each other...
彼此分享爱...
And pretend not to know...
还假装不知道...
While I live alone in my own home?
当我一个人住在自己家里时？
Kian.
基安.
The servants in the bell garden seem to be too busy...
钟花园的仆人们 似乎太忙了……
And forget it.
忘记它吧。
Qianzhi, tell someone to urge you tomorrow.
千之， 明天让人催你。
Why ask about the divorce papers signed by the young master...
为什么要问少爷签署的离婚协议书……
It hasn't been sent here yet.
还没送到这里呢。
Did you go to the temple to see Young Master?
你去庙里见少爷了吗？
correct.
正确的。
I'm done with you now
我现在已经和你结束了
I'll have someone bring my stuff back ...
我会让人把我的东西拿回来 ...
And my men will be at the bell residence tomorrow.
我的人 明天就会到钟楼。
Now let's break it all down...
现在让我们把这一切分解...
Because we will never meet again.
因为我们 再也不会见面了。
Kian, are you done?
基恩，你完成了吗？
let me go
让我走
- Let go. - Kian!
- 松手。 - 基安！
How dare you, you rude boy!
你怎么敢， 你这个粗鲁的孩子！
Get out!
出去！
Hua Rongzhou is my bodyguard.
华荣舟是我的保镖。
You cannot command him.
你不能命令他。
Please don't disturb me.
请不要打扰我。
I only take orders from my mistress.
我只听从我的女主人的命令。
Get out of here, Zhong Yeran!
钟野然，滚出去！
What are you doing, are you bothering me?
你在做什么， 打扰我了吗？
You've already made your choice, so don't be swayed.
你已经做出了选择，所以不要动摇。
Do you really want to get kicked out?
你真的想被赶出去吗？
Hua Chen.
华晨.
Because you insist that I divorce ...
因为你坚持要我离婚 ...
Okay...
好的...
do whatever you want.
做你想做的。
Jong-ye is...
钟业是...
When you return, deliver the message to Mu Yao.
回来后，将消息传递给慕瑶。
He owed...
他欠...
Now I have two lives.
现在我有两种生活。
Did Zhong Yeran hit you hard?
钟业然对你打击很大吗？
Are you hurt?
你受伤了吗？
You don't look good.
你看起来不太好。
I'm doing great.
我很好。
If something like this happens again...
如果再发生这样的事情……
Don't act hastily...
先别急着行动...
And just do as I tell you.
并且按照我告诉你的去做。
Otherwise, instead of helping me...
不然的话，不是帮我...
You will harass me.
你会骚扰我。
I can finish it...
我可以完成它...
My own problem.
我自己的问题。
You need to see a therapist.
你需要去看治疗师。
It feels really fresh now...
现在感觉真的很新鲜...
After the commotion with Jong Ye-ran.
与钟艺兰的骚动之后。
Qianzhi, please help me prepare.
千智，请帮我准备一下。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
Judge Don.
法官唐.
Have the murderers been caught ?
凶手被抓到了吗 ？
Assassins appear...
刺客出现...
At the Mid-Autumn Festival...
中秋佳节之际...
He committed suicide after being arrested.
他被捕后自杀了。
No one is safe.
没有人是安全的。
You once said...
你曾经说过...
The Ge family escaped...
葛家 逃了出来……
It's under your control.
它在你的控制之下。
First, the murderers stole our perfume recipe...
首先，凶手 偷走了我们的香水配方……
During ancestral prayer meeting.
举行祭祖祈福会时。
Then a massacre occurred...
然后，一场屠杀发生了……
At the Mid-Autumn Festival banquet.
中秋宴会上。
They come and go easily .
他们来去容易 。
At the Mid-Autumn Festival banquet...
中秋宴会上...
The butlers of the head family...
一家之主的管家……
Come together and celebrate...
一起 庆祝吧...
But it was a golden opportunity for the assassins...
但这对刺客来说却是一个千载难逢的机会……
To kill us all.
杀掉我们所有人。
If your mom got hurt in this incident...
如果你妈妈在这次事件中受伤...
How will you report this to the government?
您将如何向政府报告此事？
Teacher Jongyoung.
钟永老师。
We couldn't catch all the culprits...
我们没能抓住所有的罪魁祸首...
I discovered something strange...
我发现了一些奇怪的事情...
About this attack.
关于这次袭击。
more?
更多的？
Judge Don.
法官唐.
You really discovered a lot.
你真的发现了很多。
Actually, since last year...
其实从去年开始...
The Ge family has been inactive for a long time.
葛家已经很久没有活动了。
But after causing an uproar at the memorial service...
但 在追悼会上引起轩然大波之后……
And murder...
还有谋杀...
At the Mid-Autumn Festival...
中秋佳节之际...
Their movements...
他们的动作……
I'm getting more and more suspicious.
我越来越怀疑了。
After completing the ancestral rites...
完成祭祀仪式后...
We have expanded our search.
我们扩大了搜索范围。
So what I can guarantee is...
所以我能保证的是...
No more than 5 people can escape...
最多只能逃出5个人……
And hide in the city.
并躲进城里。
Dozens of assassins appeared at the banquet...
宴会上出现了数十名刺客……
But you said...
但你说...
Can't there be more than 5 people?
人数不能超过5人吗？
The second strange thing is...
第二个奇怪的事情是……
What I want to talk about.
我想谈什么。
Assassins' clothes and weapons...
刺客的衣服和武器...
It's not like before.
和以前不一样了。
After checking with the driver...
与司机核实后...
And there is an experienced clothing store owner in the neighborhood...
而且附近还有一位经验丰富的服装店老板......
I'm sure...
我敢肯定...
They come from two different groups.
他们来自两个不同的群体。
Two different groups?
两个不同的群体？
correct.
正确的。
Those who attack the ancestral rites...
那些攻击祖先仪式的人……
Comes from the Ge family.
出身于葛家。
Meanwhile, the other groups...
与此同时，其他小组……
Maybe there aren't enough people...
可能人还不够吧...
So they could only hire temporary help.
所以他们 只能雇临时帮手。
Besides, they are in a hurry.
此外，他们很着急。
That's why there's a big difference.
这就是为什么存在很大的差异。
As I said earlier...
正如我之前所说...
Someone inside helps them.
里面有人 帮助他们。
remember...
记住...
When Teacher Wu came to town...
当吴老师进城时...
He tried several times...
他尝试了好几次...
Asking Mrs. Jong on a date...
向 Jong 女士询问约会...
And that's very strange.
这很奇怪。
You suspect...
你怀疑...
Is it my senior or the Hua Family?
是我前辈还是华家？
I'm just expressing my doubts.
我只是表达我的疑问。
No wonder you can't find anything .
难怪你找不到任何东西 。
You're targeting the wrong people!
你瞄准了错误的人！
Murder at the banquet...
宴会上的凶杀案……
It must have been planned in advance.
一定是提前计划好的。
They won't look for extra people at the last minute.
他们不会在最后一刻寻找额外的人手。
If the two groups cooperate as you said...
如果两个团体像你说的那样合作的话......
At least they will...
至少他们会...
Match your clothes and weapons.
匹配你的衣服和武器。
How could they make such a big mistake...
他们怎么 会犯这么大的错误……
So can you find it?
那么你能找到吗？
Please give me a moment, Master Jongyoung.
请给我一点时间， 钟永大师。
We will work hard to find the culprit.
我们将努力找出罪魁祸首。
I still don't know...
我还是不知道...
Are there two groups of assassins at the banquet?
宴会上有两伙刺客吗？
So please keep this a secret.
所以请保守秘密。
I don't want to warn the enemy.
我不想警告敌人。
composure. My lips are locked.
镇静。我的嘴唇被锁住了。
Would you like to go, madam?
女士，您想去吗？
You need to take a bodyguard with you.
你需要带一名保镖随行。
not needed. I don't want anyone to know.
不需要。 我不想让任何人知道。
Can I come with you, ma'am?
我可以和你一起去吗，女士？
of course.
当然。
Young Master.
少爷。
Someone there sent another message.
那里有人 又发来一条消息。
Come closer.
靠近点。
Young Master.
少爷。
There are too many people watching Judge Wang...
看王法官的人太多了……
And they are watching his every move closely.
他们 正在密切关注他的一举一动。
In the end, my eyes were focused on him...
最后， 我的目光集中在了他的身上……
You can investigate secretly.
你可以秘密调查。
Do you know the number of bodyguards...
你知道保镖有多少吗？
Of all the households in town.
镇上所有的家庭。
to find out...
找出...
Where do these murderers come from?
这些凶手从哪里来？
Okay, Young Master.
好的，少爷。
Makam Huashen
Makam Huashen
What is that?
那是什么？
It's pretty scary here at night.
这里晚上 还是挺吓人的。
What if we were next to your wife ?
如果我们在你妻子旁边怎么办 ？
This is Young Master Hua.
这是华少爷。
There is nothing scary.
没什么可怕的。
sisters.
姐妹。
It's late again.
又晚了。
I don't want to take you to the grave with everyone else...
我不想把你和其他人一起送进坟墓……
So I came alone.
于是我就一个人来了。
He said we would talk after the banquet.
他说我们宴会结束后再谈。
This time I kept my promise.
这次我兑现了我的承诺。
You wouldn't blame me , would you?
你不会责怪我 吧？
This delicious wine...
这美味的酒...
It is going through a long maturation process .
它正在经历一个漫长的成熟过程 。
Please be nice to my sister
请对我妹妹好一点
Here's a toast to you.
这是为你干杯。
Your brother is taking care of you.
你哥哥正在照顾你。
I'll be back, brother.
我会回来的，兄弟。
Let's meet again next time.
我们下次再见面吧。
How long has Muda been standing here ?
穆达在这里站了多久了 ？
It's only been 30 minutes.
才过了30分钟。
How do you know I'm here?
你怎么知道我在这里？
I know your heart is soft.
我知道你的心是柔软的。
You never stay still...
你永远不会静止不动...
When Hua Shen was in trouble.
当华神陷入困境时。
Others think you didn't attend the funeral...
其他人认为你没有参加葬礼...
Because it's heartless.
因为没心没肺。
But I am sure...
但我确信...
You are coming.
你来了。
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
I have something prepared for you.
我为你准备了一些东西。
Surat Perserian
苏拉特波斯语
Just ask the servant to bring it to you .
只要叫仆人给你拿过来就可以了。
You do not need to come in person.
您无需亲自前来。
i miss you.
我想你。
This is inappropriate, Young Master.
这是不合适的，少爷。
late. I'd better go back.
晚的。 我最好还是回去吧
Are there any traces of the culprit?
是否还有罪魁祸首的踪迹？
At the banquet that day?
那天的宴会上？
Not yet.
还没有。
They erased all traces.
他们抹去了所有痕迹。
The caught murderers chose to take their own lives...
被捕的凶手 选择了自杀……
By poisoning yourself.
通过毒害自己。
No one is safe.
没有人是安全的。
They also left no traces at the crime scene.
他们 在犯罪现场也没有留下任何痕迹。
Besides, it's always difficult...
而且，总是很难...
Looking for the Ge family.
寻找葛家。
Military law was once again imposed on the city.
军法再次 强加于这座城市。
Has the culprit been caught?
罪魁祸首抓到了吗？
Are they wearing the same clothes and carrying the same weapons?
他们穿着同样的衣服， 携带同样的武器吗？
Why are you asking this?
你为什么问这个？
It seems less harmonious.
显得不太和谐。
Even among themselves there are disputes.
甚至他们之间也存在争议。
It's as if their goals are different.
就好像他们的目标不同一样。
The ability to remain calm in any situation...
在任何情况下都能保持冷静的能力...
surprising.
奇怪。
You don't have to say anything if you don't want to.
如果您不愿意，您不必说什么。
Don't ignore me by saying things like that.
别说这种话无视我。
Kian.
基安.
Even if it's just the two of us...
哪怕只有我们两个人...
This is inappropriate behavior.
这是不恰当的行为。
What do you think about me?
你觉得我怎么样？
Don't you always know how I feel?
你不是一直都知道我的感受吗？
But now you've given me the rules.
但现在你给了我规则。
Young Master, when did you change your goals?
少爷，你什么时候改变目标了？
Nothing has changed.
什么也没有变。
Always you.
总是你。
What about Muyao?
慕瑶呢？
Why do you keep linking me with that person?
你为什么老把 我和那个人联系起来？
You said...
你说...
The way we look at that person is different...
我们看待这个人的方式不一样...
Compared to the way you see me.
与你看到我的方式相比。
Of course it's different.
当然是不同的。
I see you differently...
我对你的看法不一样了...
Because I like you.
因为我喜欢你。
That never changes.
这永远不会改变。
Behind the rock garden earlier...
早些时候在假山花园后面……
You mentioned Mu Yao. What does it mean?
你提到了穆瑶。 这是什么意思？
Mu Yao is a special woman...
慕瑶 是一个特别的女人……
Wu Shuomo also liked it.
吴硕模也很喜欢。
Young Master, this is a reminder for you.
少爷，这是给您的一个提醒。
How do I know?
我怎么知道？
A man cannot hide his affection for his lover.
男人无法隐藏对爱人的感情。
The way you look at Mu Yao and me...
你看我和慕瑶的眼神……
Very different.
非常不一样。
Women are sensitive to such things.
女人对这样的事情很敏感。
Of course, the way I look at Mu Yao is...
当然，我看慕瑶的眼神是……
It's not the way I see you.
这不是我看你的方式。
I still remember the married woman...
我还记得那个已婚女人...
Also you.
还有你。
He is married.
他已经结婚。
Are you still thinking about it?
你还在想吗？
of.
的。
She is a lucky woman.
她是一个幸运的女人。
And the person I want to make clothes for ...
还有我想为之做衣服的人 ...
The same goes for you.
你也一样。
It's done.
完成。
I want to make clothes for her .
我想给她做衣服 。
You and that person have the same build.
你和那个人 有相同的身材。
Because you are here...
因为你在这里...
Can you help me with the size?
你能帮我看看尺寸吗？
The only thing I like is you...
我唯一喜欢的就是你...
until now.
到目前为止。
Kian.
基安.
I... I'm Mr. I married Mr.
我……我是先生。我嫁给了先生。
I knew it would be burdensome...
我就知道这会是一个负担...
Because of your condition...
因为你的条件...
So, I didn't tell you...
所以，我没有告诉你...
Until divorce.
直到离婚。
You once used Mu Yao as an excuse...
你曾经 拿慕瑶当借口……
To reject me.
来拒绝我。
But why does the expression...
但为什么这个表情...
Do you feel like you don't know anything now?
你现在是不是感觉自己什么都不知道了？
Because I understood what I meant last time...
因为我明白了上次的意思...
Why are you here today?
你今天为什么在这里？
You are back to your normal self...
你又恢复正常了……
Fah's daughter...
法的女儿...
And there are no more obstacles...
并且不再有任何障碍......
So I came here to ask.
所以我才来这里问问。
Young Master, are you kidding?
少爷，你开玩笑吧？
Think about our identity.
想想我们的身份。
We are not suitable for each other even now.
即使现在我们也不合适。
Maybe it's not appropriate...
也许不太合适...
Let's talk about it here and now .
我们现在就在这里讨论一下吧 。
But I want to know how you feel
但我想知道你的感受如何
If you have any affection for me...
如果你对我还有一点感情的话...
Leave the other work to me.
其他的工作就交给我吧。
Then I will make sure you accompany me properly.
那我就保证你好好陪我。
Have you seen the young master?
你见过少爷吗？
What do you see?
你看到了什么？
Kian.
基安.
Leave it to me.
交给我。
Expropriate...
征用...
And I am here for you.
我在这里等你。
Can I hold your hand?
我可以握住你的手吗？
Adigan Bonus
阿迪甘奖金
Please refine the ink for me.
请为我炼墨。
Surat Perserian
苏拉特波斯语
This is what he wants.
这就是他想要的。
Let Lin Jiang watch over them.
让林江看管他们。
Okay, Young Master.
好的，少爷。
Young Master, Teacher Meng is outside.
少爷，孟老师在外面。
Tell him to come in.
叫他进来。
Hello, Young Master.
少爷您好。
What is that?
那是什么？
His Majesty asked me to deliver some food.
陛下 让我送一些食物。
OK. Just put it down.
好的。把它放下吧。
I'm busy.
我很忙。
If you have nothing else, you can go.
如果你没有别的事， 你就可以走了。
Okay, Young Master.
好的，少爷。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。